<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Dr Olga Perski</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conceptualisation, measurement and promotion of engagement with digital behaviour change interventions</title>
      <link>/project/engagement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/engagement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first started working on the problem of engagement with digital behaviour change interventions as part of my MSc project (2014-2015). Here, I explored users’ &lt;a href=&#34;https://shop.bps.org.uk/health-psychology-update-vol-26-no-1-spring-2017&#34;&gt;real-world engagement&lt;/a&gt; with a novel smoking cessation app, BupaQuit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;https://discovery.ucl.ac.uk/id/eprint/10063428/&#34;&gt;PhD thesis&lt;/a&gt; (2015-2018) comprised 6 studies and aimed to gain a better understanding of how to define, measure and promote engagement with digital interventions in general, and with apps for smoking cessation and alcohol reduction in particular. As part of this work, I led &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/tbm/article/7/2/254/4563238&#34;&gt;an interdisciplinary, systematic review&lt;/a&gt; and generated a two-part, integrative definition of digital engagement and a conceptual framework. I used semi-structured interviews and online surveys to develop &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/tbm/article/10/1/267/5423758&#34;&gt;a self-report measure of digital engagement&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jmir.org/2019/11/e16197/&#34;&gt;evaluated&lt;/a&gt; the new measure in two different populations. I also conducted &lt;a href=&#34;https://bmcmedinformdecismak.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12911-017-0422-8&#34;&gt;a think aloud and interview study&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/2055207618785841&#34;&gt;a focus group study&lt;/a&gt; to gain a better understanding of factors that influence engagement with apps for smoking cessation alcohol reduction, in addition to &lt;a href=&#34;https://mhealth.jmir.org/2019/10/e14098/&#34;&gt;a series of N-of-1 studies&lt;/a&gt;, harnessing smartphone-enabled daily ecological momentary assessments, to explore within-person fluctuations in psychological and behavioural variables (e.g. motivation, extent of alcohol consumption) and their associations with users’ app engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my post-doctoral training, I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly persuaded that emerging technologies (e.g. chatbots, virtual reality) and novel intervention designs (e.g. hybrid human-digital interventions, &amp;lsquo;just-in-time adaptive interventions&amp;rsquo;) have potential for counteracting the observed ‘engagement crisis’. In collaboration with the architect of &lt;a href=&#34;https://smokefreeapp.com/&#34;&gt;the Smoke Free app&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve conducted &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/2055207619880676&#34;&gt;an experimental study&lt;/a&gt; with &amp;gt;55,000 smokers to examine the added effect of a supportive chatbot underpinned by artificial intelligence on user engagement and short-term quit success. The results were positive, with the addition of the chatbot more than doubling rates of engagement and increasing self-reported quit success at a 1-month follow-up. I&amp;rsquo;m currently leading a qualitative process evaluation which forms part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://bmjopen.bmj.com/content/10/11/e036568&#34;&gt;a feasibility study&lt;/a&gt; of a hybrid human-digital smoking cessation intervention, integrated in the UK thoracic surgical pathway, and a feasibility study of a brief virtual reality scenario for smokers unmotivated to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development, optimisation and evaluation of apps for smoking cessation and alcohol reduction</title>
      <link>/project/smoking_apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/smoking_apps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m regularly involved in the development, optimisation and evaluation of apps for smoking cessation and alcohol reduction, including the evaluation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mdpi.com/1660-4601/15/2/288&#34;&gt;digitally enabled personal carbon monoxide monitors and related smoking cessation apps&lt;/a&gt;, the refinement of the content and design of &lt;a href=&#34;https://drinklessalcohol.com/&#34;&gt;the Drink Less app&lt;/a&gt; and the evaluation of the popular Smoke Free app in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/add.14652&#34;&gt;parallel-arm, randomised controlled trial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smoking, vaping and COVID-19</title>
      <link>/project/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/covid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic, I&amp;rsquo;m co-leading a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.qeios.com/read/UJR2AW.10&#34;&gt;living evidence review&lt;/a&gt; (updated 9 times to-date, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/add.15276&#34;&gt;version 7&lt;/a&gt; published in a peer-reviewed journal) on the association of smoking status with SARS-CoV-2 infection, hospitalisation, disease severity and mortality, which is updated every other month. Each update is shared directly with Public Health England’s tobacco control team and Action on Smoking &amp;amp; Health. I&amp;rsquo;m also co-leading a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.11.26.20238469v1.full&#34;&gt;case-control study&lt;/a&gt; at a single UK hospital site to examine the association of smoking status with hospitalisation for COVID-19 compared with other respiratory viruses a year previous, and contribute to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ucl-covid19research.co.uk/&#34;&gt;large survey study&lt;/a&gt; to gain a better understanding of the impact of COVID-19 on smoking, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.medrxiv.org/content/10.1101/2020.12.01.20241760v1&#34;&gt;vaping&lt;/a&gt; and alcohol consumption among UK adults.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic review of Ecological Momentary Assessment (EMA) studies of five public health-related behaviours</title>
      <link>/project/ema_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/ema_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m co-leading a large systematic review of ecological momentary assessment (EMA) studies targeting five public health-related behaviours, including smoking, alcohol, physical activity, dietary behaviours and sexual health-related behaviours. Findings from this review are expected to inform design decisions in future observational EMA studies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UCL Smoking and Alcohol Toolkit Studies</title>
      <link>/project/smoking-toolkit-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/smoking-toolkit-study/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
